Grinches Are Scary, Or So Everyone Hears, But One
Little Boy Overcomes His Worst Fears!
Halloween Is Grinch Night is a fantasy, family,
animation film directed by Gerard Baldwin.
When the sour-sweet wind starts blowing again, the Whos retreat to their
homes because they know the Grinch will soon be a'prowlin.
Young Eukariah Who has to make a trip to the Euphemism (outhouse), when the
wind blows him away to a confrontation with the gruesome Grinch.
Eukariah decides that the Grinch must be stopped, so he faces his
fears and confronts the Grinch and his spooks.
The Grinch / Narrator (voice), played by Hans Conried.
Josiah (voice), played by Hal Smith.
Euchariah (voice), played by Gary Shapiro.
Mariah (voice), played by Irene Tedrow.
Sgt. Samuel McPherson (voice), played by Jack DeLeon.
Max (voice), played by Henry Gibson.
Halloween Is Grinch Night (titled It's Grinch Night for the 1992 videocassette release and Grinch Night for the sing-a-long videocassette release) is a
1977 children's animated Halloween television special and is a prequel to the 1966 television special How the Grinch Stole Christmas!
It premiered on ABC on October 28, 1977.
Boris Karloff, the original voice actor for The Grinch, had died and was replaced by Hans
Conried, with Thurl Ravenscroft singing as he did in the original special.
The songs and score were written by Sesame Street composer Joe Raposo.
The special won the 1978 Primetime Emmy Award for
Outstanding Children's Program.
The film explores themes of holiday, halloween, musical,
based on children's book, short film.
The tone is lighthearted.